# Summary

In my 10+ years in public service I have focused on software and application development. More recently, I've played major roles in project management attaining my Project Management Professional and Certified ScrumMaster certification and a Navy Superior Civilian Service award. I'm currently enrolled in an Executive Potential Program, a competency-based leadership development program focused on leading change.

# Work Experience

## **Defense Media Activity**

# IT Specialist - Navy Chief of Web

07/2017 - Present

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

Led cross functional teams of designers, developers, QA specialists to modernize Navy websites and mobile
apps to allow the members of the Navy public affairs community to easily create and distribute content across
the Navy enterprise.

Navy Flagship website
Navy All Hands website

The Official US Navy App: IOS

The Official US Navy App: Android (January 2022)

· Lead website migration resulting in Navy Superior Civilian Service award

## Selective Service System

# IT Specialist - Project Manager / Developer

12/2015 - 07/2017

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

 Led team of developers and database administrators in a business process improvement effort improving the system that rapidly provides personnel into the armed forces in the event of a national emergency

#### **TASKS**

- Developed and managed SSS mission-critical project articulating areas improvement and bringing project development expertise in-house
- Directed 508 compliance initiative focusing on video portions of public website ensuring people with disabilities have access to electronic and information technology

### Internal Revenue Service

### IT Specialist - Project Manager / Developer

01/2011 - 12/2015

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

 Led development team building desktop applications to collect and compute statistical data that informs other government agencies and the public how the tax system works

#### **TASKS**

- Produced electronic correspondence tracking system to take place of time consuming paper signing process resulting in Special Act Award
- Led team of programmers to convert program from Oracle Forms to Visual Studio NET in a Project Manager role increasing security measures and coding efficiencies
- Played lead role in cross-divisional team to build agency framework & templates to improve efficiency of developer programming

### **Holabird Sports**

Web / Graphics Designer 03/2007 - 05/2011

**ACCOMPLISHMENTS** 

Increased brand/product awareness through traditional print and digital web advertising

#### **TASKS**

- Assisted with web redesign through analysis of user experience tests increasing conversion rates in purchasing process
- Increased brand/product awareness through traditional and digital advertising using Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator
- Promoted sales with technical product descriptions using creative writing skills

### Education

## Georgia Institute of Technology

Master's degree Computer and Information Sciences and Support Services 2022-

## **Towson University**

Bachelor's Computer Information Systems 2010 - 2011

# The Community College of Baltimore County

Interactive Design Certificate Computer Graphics and Visual Communication 2004 – 2007

# Volunteer

Assistant coach of youth soccer, baseball and basketball